Noah McDougall, PMP

Cell: (865) 323-3873 | Email: noah.mcdougall@gmail.com
Website: www.linkedin.com/in/noahmcdougall/
Github: https://github.com/noahmcdougall/

SUMMARY

Applied geoscientist experienced in project management, oil and gas, mining, and geographic information systems. Adept at focusing technical and planning skills to achieve business results. Specializes in project management, seismic interpretation, spatial analysis, and automating tasks using advanced Excel knowledge and basic scripting in Python.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nyrstar Tennessee Mines, Gordonsville, TN – Exploration Geologist

 $2017 \rightarrow$

Geoscientist guiding exploration operations for Gordonsville, Elmwood, and Cumberland mines.

- Managed up to 25 contractors and six rigs for surface and underground drilling programs.
- QC/QA of core logging operations and assay sample preparations.
- Developed strong relationships with community landowners as acting landman.
- Data processing and GIS increased surface hole success rate by 10x over 2018.
- Led gravity survey project to map breccia systems from initiation to closing.

LandWorks, Houston, TX – Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Team Lead 2016–17 GIS mapping team lead supporting land management needs for various energy industry clients.

- Supervised a team tasked with mapping utility easements from legal documents.
- Developed ArcGIS add-ins using Python that save an estimated \$75K per life of project.
- Managed building an ArcGIS Online project and web portal for an alternative energy client.

BP, Houston, TX – Integrated Geophysicist

2013-16

Geoscientist in charge of reserve estimates, seismic reprocessing, model building, well planning and monitoring, and activity planning across three major Gulf of Mexico fields.

- Coordinated technical planning of a 4D seismic acquisition program.
- Worked with reservoir engineers to optimize the water injection program and future production.
- Built structurally complex, static reservoir Petrel model and model-building workflows.
- Reinterpreted reserve estimates for government compliance and Resource Support Package that led to major well design and activity plan updates.
- Designed the standard for Integrated Subsurface Description documentation and leveraged ArcGIS skills to standardize maps across reservoirs.

EDUCATION

Proiect Managem	nent Professional – PMP # 2171866	2018→
BP Challenger Training Program – Integrated Geophysicist		2013–16
	University of Arizona	2011–13
	GPA: 3.81/4.0	
B.S. Geology,	University of Tennessee, Knoxville	2007-11
	GPA: 3.89/4.0, Summa Cum Laude	
RESEARCH P	ROJECTS	
	offshore Guinea post-rifting structures – plateau extension unism" - Graduate project (GSA 2013)	2011–13
ground penetral	ived correlation between ground conductivity and 100 MHz ting radar depth attenuation" - Undergraduate project, presented ional conference (SAGEEP 2011)	2011
"Multi-tool geophysical investigation of karst features on intramural fields of the University of Tennessee, Knoxville" - Undergraduate project		
HONORS and	AWARDS	
Edith L. Moore N	ature Sanctuary Volunteer ArcGIS Manager, Houston	2015–17
Secretary of the Greater Houston Grotto		
Vice President of the UAGS (SEG sponsored club)		
Outstanding Graduate in Commencement Program		2011
Chancellor's Honors Extraordinary Professional Promise Award		2011
Undergraduate G	eoClub President	2010–11
SOFTWARE E	XPERIENCE	

Experience using many forms of industry software including:

 Landmark Software 	 Roxar RMS 	 AcQuire GIM Suite
• Petrel	LeapFrog	 DGI CoViz
 IHS Kingdom 	 MineSight 3D 	• QGIS
• ESRI ArcGIS	Surfer	

Proficient in other drafting software such as Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop. Self-taught in Python, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, jQuery, Jade, Node JS, Gulp, and Git.